来い
Come!
「月下獣・半人半虎」
Beast Beneath the Moonlight!
Rashoumon Demonic Armor!
「羅生門・天魔纏鎧」
Come on, now.
おいおい
I don't want to have spent
all that money on nothing.
これでは張った金額に遠く及ばんぞ
三分を切った
Three minutes left.
Kyouka-chan, if you'd prefer, I can
set you up with a life of killing.
鏡花ちゃん
君が望むなら
殺しで生きる道を用意してやってもいい
けど　君の苦悩は君だけのものじゃない
But your anguish isn't yours alone.
成りたいものと向いているものが違う時
What should one do, when what they
want to be isn't what they're best at?
人はどうすればいい
Everyone fights, searching for the
correct way to live their lives.
生き方の正解を知りたくて　誰もが戦ってる
What do they seek by fighting?
何を求め戦う
How ought they live?
どうやって生きる
No one can say.
答えは誰も教えてくれない
我々にあるのは迷う権利だけだ
All we have is the right to waver.
溝底を往く迷い犬達のように
Like stray dogs that have hit rock bottom.
まさか
No!
人虎
Weretiger!
若し　彼の云う通りなら
If he's right...
It is worthless.
ああ　くだらぬ
The words of your past are fundamentally
unrelated to who you are now.
何故なら　苦しめる過去の言葉と貴様は　本質的に無関係だからだ
若し今日この荷物を降ろして善いのなら
If I may shed away my burden now, I will...
僕は…
Die, weretiger!
砕け　人虎
限界だ
I'm spent.
If he stands back up...
若しこれで　奴が立ち上がったら…
勝ったぞ　ゼルダ
I won, Zelda.
Wait for me.
待っていてくれ
もう一度…君に…幸福を…
I'll bring you happiness once more.
そうだ　制御端末
Right, the control terminal.
愚者め
You fool.
I took it from him during the last attack.
最後の攻撃の刹那　奴から抜き取った
Dammit!
おい
は…早く止めないと
We need to stop it!
I'd love to rip you to shreds right now but,
unfortunately, I've used up all my strength.
今すぐ八つ裂きにしてやりたいが
生憎力を使い果たした
You'll have to make do with this.
これで我慢しておけ
You're going to pay for
this when we next meet.
お前　次会ったら覚えとけ
下降？
Descending?
It can't be.
そんな　何もしてないのに
I haven't done anything.
Hand it over.
寄越せ
It isn't responding.
操作を受け付けぬ
Something's going on.
何かが起こっている
No good.
駄目だ　こっちの操作も受け付けない
It isn't responding here, either.
It's going to fall!
このままじゃ落ちるぞ
この声…
That voice...
We're out of time.
もう時間がない　何か手を考えないとみんなが…
We need to do something, or everyone's dead.
It's no use.
無駄じゃ
Someone has infiltrated from the outside.
外部から何者かが侵入し　管制を奪っておる
They've taken control.
そんな…
No.
There's still a way.
まだ方法はある
That voice...
この声…
Kyouka-chan?!
鏡花ちゃん
そちらの状況は聞いた
I heard about the situation.
「白鯨」の再浮上は無理でも　大質量で無理矢理叩き落とせば
Even if the Moby Dick can't
be stopped from falling,
with enough force from above, it can be
destroyed before it reaches the city.
街に届く前に墜落させられる
I'll use this drone.
この無人機を使う
I see.
そうか　凄いよ鏡花ちゃん
That's amazing, Kyouka-chan.
これでみんな助かる
We can save everyone.
落下傘の準備をお願いします
Prepare the parachutes, please.
君も早く脱出するんだ
You need to escape now, too.
I can't.
無理
私は虜囚
I'm captive here.
My ankles are chained down.
足首が鎖で繋がれているから
I can't make it to the evacuation system.
脱出装置のある処まで行けない
そんな…じゃあ…
No...
Then...
私のことは諦めて
Forget about me.
No!
駄目だ
そんなの駄目だ　軌道を変えるんだ
I won't allow it!
Change course!
I didn't have a single
ray of light until now.
これまで私には一片の光もなかった
But today, I understood. I have choices.
でも　今日わかった
私にも選択肢はあると
If I sacrifice myself to save everyone
else, I'll pass the entrance exam.
命を犠牲にしてみんなを助ければ　きっと私は入社試験に合格できる
I can really become a
member of the Agency.
本当に探偵社員になれる
なら　何も惜しくはない
I would regret nothing.
Stop it!
やめるんだ
Let go!
放せ　芥川
Akutagawa!
Kyouka-chan, listen to me!
鏡花ちゃん　聞いてくれ
ありがとう
Thank you.
ごめんなさい
I'm sorry.
Kyouka-chan!
鏡花ちゃん
どうして…
Why?
どうして彼女が…
Why her?
Kyouka...
鏡花
What a fool.
愚か者め
If she hadn't embraced the hope of living in
light, she wouldn't have had to die in vain.
光に生きる希望さえ抱かなければ　無駄に散らずに済んだものを
This is how it ought to
have been, Atsushi-kun.
これでよかったのだよ　敦君
太宰さん
Dazai-san.
Boss?
社長？
鏡花ちゃんは自分に克ち　街を救った
Kyouka-chan overcame herself
and saved the city.
探偵社に相応しい高潔さでね
With the high-mindedness
expected of the Agency.
でも　彼女が死ななくちゃならない理由なんてどこにも…
But there was no reason she had to die.
True, this is a merciless conclusion.
確かに厳しすぎる結末だね
でも　そうしなくてはならない理由があったのだよ
But there was a reason that
it had to be this way.
私の異能力「人上人不造」は
My ability, All Men Are Created Equal,
has an effect only on my subordinates...
That is, on members of the Agency.
私の部下　つまり探偵社員にのみ発動する
その効果は異能の出力を調節し　制御を可能にする力だ
The ability allows for control over the
output of the abilities of another.
敦君が虎の異能力をある程度操れるようになったのも探偵社に入ったからだ
The reason you're able to control your tiger
abilities now is because you joined the Agency.
そして鏡花ちゃんは入社試験に合格した
And Kyouka-chan passed the entrance exam.
衝突の直前にね
Right in the instant before the impact.
Do you understand what that means?
それがどういうことかわかるかい
白雪の刀で鎖を斬って脱出した
I used Demon Snow's katana to
cut the chain and escape.
ただいま
I'm back.
おかえり
Welcome back.
痛い
You're hurting me.
ご…ごめん
Sorry.
悪かったね　二人とも　秘密にして
Sorry I kept it from you both.
If I hadn't, it wouldn't have
made for a proper entrance exam.
そうでないと　入社試験の審査にならなかったから
最後は山？
Do we end in the mountains?
At sea.
海だ
Roger.
了解
Was this all planned from the beginning?
もしかして最初から全部…
The enemy's been defeated,
and Kyouka-chan passed.
敵は打ち倒され　鏡花ちゃんは合格した
I'm glad it all worked out.
うまくいってよかったよ
Dazai-san!
太宰さん
There's no one left to get in my way.
最早邪魔する者はない
今日こそ僕の力を…
Please see my strength now.
I don't know.
どうかな
もう限界に近いだろう
You're at your limit now, aren't you?
何せ　ギルドの長を倒したんだ
You just defeated the
Guild's leader, after all.
That's irrelevant.
そんなこと　僕は…
I am—
You've become strong.
強くなったね
ありゃりゃ
Oh, whoops.
いい眺めじゃないか
Nice view, isn't it?
You protected it.
君が守ったんだ
君の街だ
It's your city.
Episode 24
If I May Shed Away
My Burden Now
My city, huh?
僕の街　か
横浜を巻き込んだ巨大異能力戦争も無事終結
The massive gifted war caused so
much collateral damage in Yokohama.
And it's finally over.
But the government's work
is just getting started.
ですが政府の仕事はここからが本番ですね
Cleaning up after this huge mess...
この大騒ぎの後始末
I won't be sleeping at home for days.
家で寝られるのは何日後やら
Given that, we would very much appreciate
having your help, Mr. Herman.
そんなわけで　我々としては貴方の助力を得られると大変助かるのですが
ミスター・ハーマン
I just want to watch the sea for now.
今は海を見ていたい
With your information, we won't have to
arrest Guild members who weren't part of this.
貴方の情報提供があれば　我々も無関係なギルド組員を逮捕せずに済みます
Do you think that a mere grunt like
myself would have such information?
儂如き一介の構成員に　そのような知識があると思うか
Yes.
ええ
You were the leader of the Guild
two generations ago, after all.
何せ貴方は　二代前のギルドの長ですから
若造は昔の話を持ち出したがって困る
It pains me that you young'uns always
insist on bringing up the past.
Please help us overcome
our sleep deprivation.
我々の睡眠不足解消にご協力ください
I don't need to use this, do I?
これは必要ありませんよね
「白鯨」が沈んでる姿なんて　想像したこともなかったよ
I never imagined the Moby
Dick being underwater.
It was such a nice place.
いい場所だったのに
The Moby Dick?
「白鯨」が
The Guild.
ギルドがさ
The boss is missing in action.
団長は生死不明
長を失ったギルドは混乱して内乱まで起こってるそうじゃないか
I hear there are even insurgencies within
the Guild, now that we don't have a leader.
Looks like it's time to lower
the curtain on our adventures here.
ここでの冒険活劇もエンドロールの時間ってことかな
Yeah.
But life isn't over.
でも人生は終わらない
That's true.
そうだね
I'm going to go back home and
finish working on my biography.
僕は本国に帰って　自伝執筆の続きだ
What about you guys?
君達はどうするの
I'm going to look for Lord Francis.
私はフランシス様を探します
きっと生きてる
I'm sure he's alive.
You're going back to your
family, right, John?
ジョンは家族の元に帰るんでしょ
I'm not.
帰らないよ
I have to stop the insurgency in the Guild.
ギルドの内乱を治める仕事がある
You?
君が？
意外だね
That's a surprise.
I thought you hated the boss.
君は団長のことが嫌いだと思ってた
I do.
嫌いだよ
金で人を操る人間は皆大嫌いだ
I hate anyone who controls
people with money.
But he depended on his wealth to save
his family, and this was the result.
でも　家族を救う為　富に頼り　その結果がこれだと思うと
このまま帰るというのもね
I can't bring myself to just leave.
The contract...
契約…
is finally fulfilled.
これでようやく完了
You made it, huh, Lovecraft?
無事だったのかい　ラヴクラフト
What's going to become of you now?
君はこれからどうするの
I sleep.
寝る
Who is that guy?
彼は一体何者
何者でもいいさ
What does it matter?
He's one of my few friends.
僕の数少ない友人だ
Kyouka-chan.
鏡花ちゃん
Go ahead.
どうぞ
せーの
Ready, and...
Congratulations on joining
the Agency, Kyouka-chan!
鏡花ちゃん　入社おめでとう
乾杯
Cheers!
敦
Atsushi.
怪我はどうだ
How are your injuries?
もう大丈夫です
I'm all better now.
今回お前達の行動で　街は壊滅を免れた
Your actions have saved the
city from destruction.
社の先輩として　一言云うべきだろうと思ってな
I thought I should say something,
as your senior here at the Agency.
そもそも探偵社という集団組織において　単独作戦は例外なのだ
First of all, solo operations are an
exception at group organizations such as ours.
Blah, blah, blah...
I won't tell you not to apply the experience
you gained from this in the future,
今回の成功を以降に活かすなとは云わんが
but don't dare neglect the
Agency's prime activities.
社の基本動作は疎かにするな
Likewise for Kyouka.
鏡花も同じだ
Be mindful of the fact that you are
a member of the Detective Agency,
探偵社員として自覚を持ち
決して恥ずべき行いを後に残さぬよう
and act in a way that none
would be ashamed of.
肝に銘じて行動しろ…
No kidding, Kunikida.
まったくだねぇ　国木田
どいつもこいつも　酒付き合いが悪くてねえ
You're all such buzzkills.
ちょっと付き合いな
Drink with me.
No, I'd rather not drink much.
いや　俺もそれ程には…
ほれ　一言云いたかったんだろ
Isn't there something you wanted to say?
You did well, the both of you.
二人とも　よくやったな
さあ　朝まで飲むよ
All right, let's drink all night!
そ…それはちょっと…
Please, no.
Are you telling me you can't drink with me?
恥ずべき行いを後に残すな…か
Act in a way that none
would be ashamed of, huh?
春野さん　ナオミさん
Haruno-san, Naomi-san.
すみませんでした
I'm sorry.
I did some awful things to
you thanks to Q's abilities.
Ｑの異能力を受けて　お二人に非道い事を…
自分の危うさをわかっていれば　あんなことには…
It would never have happened if
I'd known how unstable I was.
Oh, that?
あの時の
本当に　すみませんでした
I'm really sorry.
敦君
Atsushi-kun, that wasn't that bad.
ここじゃ　あの程度のこと
一々引きずっていられませんわ
We can't keep holding
on to stuff like that here.
本当に
Really?
ええ
Yes.
よかった
Thank goodness.
本当にどうかしてました　お二人にあんな非道いことをするなんて
There was something seriously wrong with
me, to have done what I did to you.
Atsushi-kun.
敦君
I've never heard about this until now.
今の話　初耳なんだけど
Atsushi-kun, what is this about?
ねぇ　敦君　どういうことなの
お…落ち着いてください　谷崎さん
Please, stay calm.
乱歩君
Rampo-kun, I brought the new piece that
you inquired about over the phone.
I can't.
ボクはどうにも落ち着けない
電話で頼まれた新作を持ってきたのであるが
あたし　もうお嫁にいけない
I'm damaged goods!
国木田
ナ　ナオミさん
Kunikida!
N-Naomi-san?!
Yosano-sensei, I think you've
had too much to drink.
与謝野女医　飲み過ぎでは…
ああ　君
Oh, hey.
Thanks for coming.
よく来たね
こんな場に吾輩を呼んでよいのであるか
A-Atsushi-kun!
Do I really belong here?
乱歩さん　社長がお呼びです
Rampo-san, the boss wants you.
吾輩は敵組織の…
I'm from an enemy organization.
I'll be right back.
すぐ戻るから　そこにいて
K-Kyouka-chan?!
Stay right there.
鏡花ちゃん
乱歩君
Rampo-kun.
What?!
飲む　国木田
Kunikida!
That was an impressive operation.
見事な策だった
W-Wait, Kyouka-chan...
ちょっと待って鏡花ちゃん
まあね
Don't make excuses, it's unmanly!
The Agency would be nothing without you.
言い訳は男らしくない
矢張り乱歩がいてこその探偵社だ
What did you tell her, Tanizaki-san?
何云ったんですか　谷崎さん
まあねまあね
キミの破廉恥なあんなことやこんなことだ
All the naughty things you did.
流石が乱歩さん
いい飲みっぷりじゃないか
まあねまあね
ナオミさん
なんかとても楽しそうであるな　カール
They seem to be having fun, huh, Karl?
国木田　飲みます
まあねまあね
He likes being
left out?
It's a '64 Romane.
ロマネの六十四年ものです
May I really?
よいのかえ
Isn't it your treasure?
秘蔵の品じゃろ
Is there a better day than today to open it?
今日よりも　こいつを開けるのに相応しい日があるってのかい　姉さん
勝利に
To victory.
こりゃ美味い
This is delicious.
Boss, how shall we punish Akutagawa?
首領　芥川の処罰はどうします
Punish?
処罰？
He was instrumental in our success.
彼は今回の成功の功労者だ
Akutagawa-kun has always been this way.
芥川君は昔からそうだよ
He runs off by himself, he causes
destruction and, in the end, he contributes the most.
独走し　破壊し　結果　最大の貢献をする
彼なりの嗅覚だろうね
He has a strong nose.
成功している限り処罰はない
So long as he continues to succeed,
there will be no punishment.
ところで紅葉君
Say, Kouyou-kun, why did you not try to
escape when you were captured by the Agency?
探偵社に囚われた時　何故逃げなかったのかね
It ought to have been easy for you.
君なら脱出は容易だったろう
I wonder why.
何故かのう
茶が美味かったからかのう
Perhaps because the tea was so delicious.
Sister, let's make a deal, as two grown-ups.
姉さん　大人の取引をしよう
I have a plan for saving Kyouka-chan.
鏡花ちゃんを助ける計画がある
What?
なに
成功すれば　彼女の命と夢を同時に守れる唯一の方法だ
If we succeed, it'll be the only way to
protect both her life and her dreams.
Dazai saw how it would all play out.
太宰は今回の結末まで凡て見えておった
What a terrifying man.
恐ろしい男じゃ
Pfft.
Kouyou-kun, you are strong.
紅葉君
君は強い
Now that your beloved Kyouka-kun is gone, it
would be difficult for me to chase you down,
君が大切にしていた鏡花君がいなくなった今
若し君がポートマフィアを去る気なら　追うのは難しいだろうな
should you decide to leave
the Port Mafia now.
Of course.
無論じゃ
じゃが生憎と　頼りない首領が組織を立て直す手伝いがあるでのう
Sadly, I must help a clumsy leader
with reestablishing the organization.
嬉しい話だが
I'm grateful, but I deal only
with those under twelve.
私の守備範囲は１２歳以下だよ
Silence.
黙れ　口を縫い合わすぞ
I'll sew your lips shut.
Dazai!
太宰　次は絶対死なす
You're so dead!
あ…あの
可愛い
It's so cute!
可愛い　こっち向いて
あれ
Hey, where's Dazai-san?
そういえば太宰さんは
変な絵だね　これなら私にも描けそうだ
What a weird painting.
I bet even I could do it.
Hirotsu-san, thanks for the help.
広津さん　例の件助かったよ
Did I do enough?
あの程度でよかったのかね
All I did was leak the Moby Dick
infiltration route to Higuchi-kun.
私は白鯨潜入を樋口君に漏らしただけだよ
If she knows, she will tell Akutagawa-kun.
彼女が知れば　芥川君に伝わる
芥川君が知れば　必ず単身で乗り込んでくる
If Akutagawa-kun knows, he
will come in by himself.
It was as I expected.
予想通りだ
そうまでして芥川君と虎の少年を引き合わせた理由は何かね
Why did you go through all that trouble
to bring Akutagawa-kun
together with the tiger boy?
I wanted to be sure.
確かめたかった
For the real disaster that's about to come.
間もなく来る本当の災厄に備える為にね
He's already on the move.
奴は既に動いている筈だ
So the destruction of the
Moby Dick was a failure.
「白鯨」の墜落には失敗しましたか
ですが　ほぼ計画通りです
Still, just about everything
is according to plan.
We succeeded in creating strife within the
Guild and recruiting talented gifteds.
ギルドに内乱を誘発させ　有能な異能力者の勧誘にも成功しましたから
I'm only helping for the time being
to fulfill my end of the deal
私は意識不明のマーガレットを治すという条件で
and have Margaret brought
back to consciousness.
一時的に手を貸しているだけです
That's fine by me, Pastor.
Fyodor D.
Ability:
Crime and
Punishment
結構です　牧師殿
Let us paint the land with the
blood of the guilty together.
共にこの地を　罪深き者の血で染めましょう
よりよき世界の為に
For a better world.
We won't be able to avoid going to war
with that demon I've fought in the past.
嘗て私が会ったあの魔人
奴との戦いは避けられないだろうからね
芥川君は単独でも十分破壊的だけど
Akutagawa-kun is formidable enough by himself,
but his abilities are most
valuable in a supporting role.
本来は後衛で真価を発揮する異能力者だ
In complementing a forward
attacker such as Atsushi-kun,
敦君のような速度と根性骨を持つ前衛を補助すれば
with his speed and toughness,
he could be a powerful ally.
凄まじい戦力になる
We'll need to be more powerful than before
in order to fight with that demon.
あの魔人と戦う為には　これまで以上に強い力が要る
Something more powerful than
the former Double Black.
嘗ての「双黒」を超える新しい力
That's those two.
それがあの二人です
太宰君
Dazai-kun, why do you
value Yokohama so dearly?
君がそれほどまでにこの横浜を大切に思っているのは何故かね
My friend said me...
古い友人に云われたんです
"You might as well side with
the people who save others."
どうせなら　人を救う側になれ
"That's at least a little more beautiful."
そのほうが幾分か素敵だ　とね
Teni Muhou.
「天衣無縫」か
僕達が守った街
The city we protected.
Worthless nonsense.
くだらぬ戯言を
みんなのいるこの街が　僕の居場所になった
This city became my home,
with all the people here.